<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trevor's Blog</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/</link><description>Recent content on Trevor's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Trevor McCormick</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 09:08:22 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trmccormick.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🏃💨 Save 230ms Page Load Time Loading Fonts and Icons Asynchronously</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/blog/asynchronous_google_fonts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 09:08:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/blog/asynchronous_google_fonts/</guid><description>How your browser downloads my website After you type in the URL to a website, some administrative magic happens behind the scenes. Here is a sketch of the entire website build, with the browser&amp;rsquo;s request and download happening on the left side of the image:
When you load a website, you can use Chrome&amp;rsquo;s DevTools
to view how your browser is downloading, organizing, and delivering content from a website to your browser.</description></item><item><title>485. Max Consecutive Ones</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/leetcode/max_consecutive_ones_485/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 20:45:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/leetcode/max_consecutive_ones_485/</guid><description>Here is my thought process and solutions for Leetcode problem 485. Max Consecutive Ones
.
Given a binary array nums, return the maximum number of consecutive 1&amp;rsquo;s in the array.
You need to do three things to solve this problem:
Determine if the current index is a 1 or a 0 Find the index ranges with consecutive 1s Compare these index ranges to find the range with the maximum length Return the length of that range I solved this problem in: Python3, Javascript, mySQL, and Java:</description></item><item><title>🟨 Leetcode Practice</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/blog/leetcode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 19:08:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/blog/leetcode/</guid><description>Links to my Leetcode solutions 2021.06.20 - 485. Max Consecutive Ones</description></item><item><title>🐍 How To Query PostgreSQL in AWS RDS with Python</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/blog/python_psql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 11:20:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/blog/python_psql/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through:
how to create a public PostgreSQL instance in RDS using free-tier how to create a table and load it with data from a csv file how to query data from that table using psycopg2 RDS The only thing you have to do in the AWS console is create a Postgres DB instance and make sure it is open to the public (just for this example).</description></item><item><title>🤞 Article Ideas</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/drafts/article_ideas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 11:20:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/drafts/article_ideas/</guid><description> Automating the Web with Python: Requests, BeautifulSoup, and Selenium https://scrapingant.com/blog/scrape-dynamic-website-with-python Adding Functionality to the Adobe Audience Manager API with Python One-Page Visualization Cheatsheet for Telling Stories with Data Data Engineering Frameworks Volume, Velocity, Variety Structured, Unstructured, Semi-structured Batch versus Streaming Storage: Data Warehouses, Data Lakes, Lakehouse Platforms Data Science Workflow: Ingest, Clean, Curate, Analyze, Democratize Removing PII Across Time Travel Versions with Databricks Amazon Connect &amp;ndash; Live Stream Phone Call Transcriptions Build a Disney+ clone for Xavier Basketball videos Xavier Basketball Scout &amp;ndash; Fast Highlights Asynchronously Loading Google Fonts: Saving 200ms Page Load</description></item><item><title>☁️ How to Study for the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate Exam</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/blog/aws_csaa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:20:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/blog/aws_csaa/</guid><description>Status I am currently scheduled to take the AWS Certified Solutions Architect exam in March 2021. I just finished taking the A Cloud Guru - AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate SAA-C02 course
, and I&amp;rsquo;m continuing to refine my knowledge gaps by building some test projects within AWS before I take the exam.
Advice so far:
read through every major service FAQ: IAM, S3, EC2, RDS, VPC, CloudFront, and Route53 draw out AWS architecture diagrams by hand, and be able to draw out full solutions by memory know the highly-available architecture best practices by heart the philosophy of the AWS business model shines through every service there are tons of resources on individual components of AWS, so if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand something, chances are there are in-depth articles explaining it</description></item><item><title>👨‍💻 How To Build a Serverless Hugo Blog on AWS for $0.51 per month</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/blog/aws_hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:20:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/blog/aws_hugo/</guid><description>This post assumes you already have some familiarity with Hugo
for building a blog, and you have set up a free-tier AWS account
. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be an expert at either Hugo or AWS to follow along with the guide below. Really the only requirement is that you&amp;rsquo;re able to follow the Hugo quick start guide
.
Below is an AWS architecture diagram I created using diagrams.net
, the free version of draw.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:19:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/about/</guid><description>This website was designed to publish thoughts, how-to&amp;rsquo;s, resources, notes, and everything in-between. I write about data and marketing.
I work in marketing technology and data engineering at General Motors. I&amp;rsquo;m leading the data activation team to build out our customer data platform.
I live in Wyandotte, Michigan with my wife Haley, and our dog Captain.
Here is me (Trevor) and my wife (Haley) in Central Park</description></item><item><title>Shortcode examples</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/shortcode_examples/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 21:19:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/shortcode_examples/</guid><description>Pre-loaded shortcodes Shortcodes
My own shortcodes Icons take arguments: svg, width, height, scale. These default to 100, 100, 1.</description></item><item><title>☁️ How to Study for the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Exam</title><link>https://trmccormick.com/blog/aws_ccp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 19:08:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://trmccormick.com/blog/aws_ccp/</guid><description>Foundations The AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Exam assumes you have some familiarity with cloud concepts. If you&amp;rsquo;re completely unfamiliar with those, it may benefit you to learn or review some introductory computing concepts. When I was in college, I completed two courses that gave me a great foundation:
Stanford CS 101 - Introduction to Computing Principles
Harvard CS50 - Introduction to Computer Science
This course features one of my favorite professors of all time &amp;ndash; David Malan
.</description></item></channel></rss>